Thank you, Dan and Deb. It's truly an honor to be here today. Before I go any
further, I'd like to, in the tradition of African culture, we always ask our
elders for permission to speak.
So, before I go any further, I'd like to ask Imam Shahid if I have permission
to proceed. Thank you.
It's an honor today to announce to you one of the giants in the city of
Cleveland who I've had the privilege and honor to get to know over the last few
years, Elle Hodge, Amir Khaled, A. Samad.
The supreme is to honor him because he's always been my friend and my brother
and my son. Amir Khaled is Samad's president of the Coalition for Better Life,
and many of you know him as "Peace in the Hood."
Khaled is the second African-American and first Muslim to be inducted into the
Cleveland International Hall of Fame. We are the field camera rockers.
We call him the ubiquitous Reverend Dr. Otis Moss Jr. receiving a song. There
are not many people that understand the historical context of African
excellence in indigenous, authentic African-American leadership in the city of
Cleveland and many urban centers across the United States of America.
In the late 1980s, Khaled was part of the formation of Coalition for Better
Life with legendary transformational leaders such as Omar Ali Vaid and the
Prime Minister himself, R.L. Jones.
Many emerging community leaders like our president mayor, the 56th Mayor of the
city of Cleveland, Mayor Frank G. Jackson, joined Khaled, Omar, and Harlan and
others to address socio-economic inequity and issues that cause and continue to
cause distress in poor urban and minority communities.
This movement led to the first ever gang summit here in Cleveland in the United
States in 1993 and was the capitalist for the historical Mid-Yam-March in 1995.
He is a minister of culture, an activist, a mentor, a friend, and a family man.
Also here he was a heck of a basketball player back in the day.
Khaled is a minister of culture because he has developed Muslim groups by using
a guide by several principles of the Nguza-Saba.
He is an activist because we are a core and oppressed people. You can count on
him to encourage them not to let, in his famous words, the whisper of self-sabotage,
the story of self-esteem, self-determination, and greatness.
He is a mentor because he has helped a countless number of men and women,
including myself, some of whom society have given up on because of their
involvement in gangs and penal institutions and the criminal industrial complex.
In their transition from, in his words, once again, "stake and think" to
understand their true self and greatness.
He is a friend to the community, but we can always count on him when something
tragic happens, rather than be the loss of innocence, a child, families who
have lost a loved one,
senseless violence by misguided individuals, chaotic situations when the
community needs steady, respected leaders and street creators to lead us
through some of the most tumultuous times our country has experienced in our
city as well.
He always speaks truth to power, with strength and grit. But most of all, he is
a family man. His friends and family are with us today.
Khalid is vigilant and loyal to the needs of his mother, staying true to
African culture and taking care of our elders.
He is a nurturer to his family members. He has four wonderful daughters who
listen to this. This is one of the most impressive things.
There are graduates from Yale, the University of Pennsylvania, Temple and
George Washington.
As a matter of fact, African American excellence has had its excellence.
I first met Khalid in the 1990s when I worked with a group of young men who
were in my rights and passes program.
My co-facilitator, the white secretary of the Senate, told me, "We have to
invite this brother to lead the Harambee circle."
I was struck by his passion, vision, focus and love for black people and all
people in general.
After knowing him for more than 20 years, Khalid Samad still has that same
passion, vision, focus and love for people.
Ladies and gentlemen, it is my honor to introduce Khalid Samad and in the
spirit of Harambee, which means joining together for a difficult tense, my
brother in the struggle, Harambee, Harambee, Harambee, Khalid Samad.
[applause]